In the short video where we will look at
black box testing and white box testing.
So what is black box testing?
Well, a good way to think about black box testing
from layman's terms is to imagine that you've
been asked to sit in your car and test the, the
lights, the indicators, and the electric windows.
So what you do?
You get in the car, you switch the
ignition on and you will press a button
to see whether the windows go up and down.
You will flick a switch to see whether the
indicators work, and then flick another switch
to see whether the lights come on or not.
You do not need to understand the electronics
behind that or, or, or what actually
is going on under the hood to make the
lights come on or make the windows go
up and down or make the indicators work.
All you need to do is you need to be able to test
those by pressing a button or flicking a switch.
So as you can see, anybody
could carry out those tests.
So black box testing in programming is
exactly the same, what you have is you have
a software product, which is on a black box.
Which means that you cannot see inside the
box, so you don't know what's in there, so
you don't understand, or you can't see the
actual code behind the application or the
element of an application that you are testing.
What you are doing is you are just looking
to see that for a given input, you will get
a specific output of the required output.
It may be several outputs, but.ultimately,
that that is all you are testing, if you input
specific information or you press a certain Key
or input a certain piece of text or do something,
do you get the output that it should give?
There's various types of black box testing,
but these can be broken down, the three
major ones are, functional testing, so
that's actually just testing the functional
requirements of the, the system so does every,
does it do what it says, does it work well?
Does it, does everything happen the way it should?
Then you've got the non-functional testing.
Now this obviously still relates to the
software, but it's all about the, the
performance of the software, the scalability
of the software, the usability of the software.
So rather than whether do you get the required
output for a given input, you also have that
element of does it work as fast as it should?
Does it take 10 minutes for you to go?
When you input into information, does it take 10
minutes for you then to get into your account,
or do you get other errors and scalability if
you've got, if, if the software needs to be
used across multiple platforms or you know,
improved or if it's designed that you've got,
you know, initially thought there'd be 5,000
users, going to be 10,000 users, or you need
to add bolt ons, can it be scaled up and the
usability feature so is it able to be used
effectively for what it was designed for?
Then you have the regression testing, so
regression testing is if you found any problems
in the functional and the non-functional testing
it then goes back to the developers or the
coders who will then carry out fixes and you
will then do the testing, the regression testing.
So that will make sure that any of the
changes haven't, you know, they've resolved
a problem, but they haven't affected
the code that was there originally.
So it may be that you get one error and then
they go away and fix it, but they fixed it
in a certain way and you still get even more
errors because it, it isn't working in relation
to the, the code that was already there.
So an example of black box testing, so testing
the login functionality of a login screen.
I'm, I'm, I'm sure you've all seen this
type of login screen before where you
have to give a username and a password.
So this is a good example of black box testing
because it's simply saying that you would
be required to input a correct username and
password, and then you would be taken to
your account or a specific page on a website.
But, as well as that, you'll also be testing
so you know what would happen if you input an
incorrect username and an incorrect password,
you should be receiving a message on the
screen telling you that and it may be also
that if you input your username and password
incorrectly three times you may be locked out
and then you have to go through to another
screen to complete a a validation process.
So this is an example of black box testing you
will test out the functionality, does it work?
No, goes back to the developer,
does it do what it says on the box?
Yes, everything that I've tested is working.
So what about the advantages and
disadvantages of black box testing?
So one of the things there is code access
is not required so you don't need to see
the code you are just testing the actual
functionality, if you look back to the example
of the the login page, all you need to see
is that login page, input the information.
You don't need to see the code behind that, and
it also, the second one there separates a user's
perspective from the developer's perspective.
So that's important because the developer
has been, um, you know taking part in the
building and the designing and the writing
of the code and, so he's got an implicit,
um, look and feel and he, he, he understands
that he's looking for certain things.
Whereas it's a case of that as the black box
tester, you've got a defined role that you
simply need to test the functionality of the
software, so it gives that definition of rules.
You can test the application with no prior
knowledge of implementation programming, so
as I mentioned earlier, anyone can do that
you don't need to know anything prior to
actually carrying out the test, and it's well
suited and efficient for large code segments.
So when you think about, um, you, you're gonna be
testing an actual element within an application.
So as we say, the the login page, there'll be an
awful lot of code behind that there'll be, could
be a thousand units of code that are, you know,
to get you to that point, so it, it is a large
piece of code that you are testing and rather
than sort of unit testing so it's very, very
efficient and very well suited to testing that.
But what about the disadvantages?
So one of the disadvantages that it's
limited coverage, so only a specific
number of tests can be performed.
So you know, you've got three tests to
perform do you get in when you enter your
information into the login screen do you get in?
You don't get in, and what happens after three?
Those are the only three tests
that you could carry out.
Um, so that comes then to the next one, which
is blind coverage so you can't test or target
specific code segments or error prone areas,
whereas somebody who was familiar with this
type of application or element within an
application may know that this certain piece,
um, is, is prone to errors or prone to bugs,
and you wouldn't know anything about that.
The test cases are difficult to design, which
is true because you have to, um, there's
an awful lot going on in the background.
So the, you know, when you things take
more time, um, it takes more costs,
there's more people involved, and the
inefficient testing, so the tester only
has limited knowledge about an application.
So it, it is a case of if you don't
know that much about an application,
you can only do certain tests.
An example, there would be the the login page,
which is quite a straightforward one, but there
will be other more complicated tests to carry out.
So that's the advantages and
disadvantages of of black box testing.
So then we'll come onto white box testing.
So again, as you can see, we've got a picture
here, but this time we've got a picture of a
mechanic as opposed to somebody sitting in a car.
The reason being is that when you're doing
white box testing, so if this gentleman was
now testing the, the lights and the indicators
and the windows, he would be able to test them
under the hood, he would be able to look at the
fundamental electronics and the systems within the
car that make those features or functions work.
So if it's not working, he knows, he can see
why it's not working as opposed to the, the,
the user who would only be able to flick a
switch or press a button, this person would
be able to go under the hood and, and look
at things in more detail and more depth.
So as opposed to black box testing where
you have no knowledge of the underlying
code, in white box testing you have
access to all aspects of the software.
So you would be able to see the code, you'd
be able to see everything that's involved or
everything that makes up that application,
which is why we have in white box testing,
uh, a nice white box with the lid open so
everything is transparent, everything is visible.
So why do you perform white box testing?
It allows you to find internal security holes.
You can see broken or poorly structured,
paths in the coding, the flow of the inputs
through the code, the expected outputs, the
functionality of conditional loops, as you can
see, all of the things here are, are elements
that you would need to have a good understanding
of the, of, of programming in general, and
also the, the code that has been written and
everything about the actual, um, application.
Again, there are advantages and
disadvantages to white box testing.
So one of the advantages that you can spot errors
and problems more quickly because you're, you
tend to be testing smaller elements of code.
Extra lines of code can be removed, which can
bring in hidden defects so again, because it's
all about efficiency, you know the code, I
can look at there and he can say, right, well,
we don't need that so we can, we can remove
those elements of, of code, find hidden bugs
more efficiently, um, and allow for greater
stability, again, you know, these people who
will be testing it in white box testers will be
very experienced, uh, programmers and testers,
and they will know what to look for.and it also
helps in optimizing the code and optimize code
tends to be more efficient and runs faster.
But there are also disadvantages, so the
higher degree of complexity involved.
Um, so due to the detailed knowledge, so what,
what you're gonna think about there is you can't
just ask any Tom, Dick, or Harry to carry out
the test they need to be somebody who has very
um, high level of experience and understanding
of the code and the programming language that
is being used, and that brings onto the next one
where that because skilled testers are needed,
it's going to cost more money, the costs are
increased, it costs far more to employ a white
box tester who has all of the skills and knowledge
and understanding of a variety of different
programming language than it does to um, ask
somebody who's just sitting in an office and
saying, can you just test this for me please?
So, again, you've also got the, the next one
it requires tools that have tighter integration
with the system being tested which, does pose a
risk of system performance being affected because
the tools that you're using to test it are very,
can be memory intensive and system, you know,
that can drain the system they can also cause
errors or problems and, which would not give you
the, the results that you would expect if you
were just doing the, the end product testing,
which is the black box testing, and no matter
what you're testing it, the last one there, it's
impossible to look into every nook and cranny to
find out the hidden errors that may be creating
problems so you can't test everything so it is
a case of that, that are disadvantages to that.
So which one would you.
So you've got your black box testing.
So this one ensures that all the different
software modules work well at a system level,
so after they've been integrated, so you've
got several components that plug them all
together, you're testing them and does everything
work as expected or the white box testing?
So again, they both have importance so this
one, you know, the white box is important to
catch defects at the, the unit level, which
is an important part of testing as we, you
know, you have looked at and we'll look at
as you work through this unit and there's
no really right or wrong you, you will
find that both of these will be utilized.
Um, but it's important to understand what each
of them does and when each of them will be used.
So just as a little test, um, I'd like you
to carry out some research because this
will be relevant to your assessment as well.
There are some other different types of testing,
so the static testing, dynamic testing, smoke
testing, sanity testing, interface testing.
What I'd like you to do is carry out some research
on each of those types of testing and one of the
things there is you've all talked about the, the,
the software development life cycle, but the, the
software testing life cycle is also important.
So these are all things that will
or may or may not happen within that
software development life cycle.
So it'd be interesting to see if you can carry
out some research, make some notes on these
as it will help you within your assessment.
Just so you can get a better handle on the various
types of testing this isn't the, you know, every
type of testing out there there's an unlimited
amount of tests that can be, um, done and new ones
are being developed all the time but you will find
it useful if you carry out a bit of research so
you understand these different types of testing.